<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?> <rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.nasa.gov/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"> <channel> <title>NASA Image of the Day</title>
 <description>The latest NASA &quot;Image of the Day&quot; image.</description>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/</link>
 <atom:link rel="self" href="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss" />
 <language>en-us</language>
 <managingEditor>yvette.smith-1@nasa.gov</managingEditor>
 <webMaster>brian.dunbar@nasa.gov</webMaster>
 <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
 <item> <title>Glow with the Flow</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/aero/flow_patterns_image.html</link>
 <description>Researchers at NASA&#039;s Langley Research Center in Hampton, Va., use all sorts of tools and techniques to learn more during the development of aircraft and spacecraft designs.
In this photo, engineers led by researcher Greg Gatlin have sprayed fluorescent oil on a 5.8 percent scale model of a futuristic hybrid wing body during tests in the14 by-22-Foot Subsonic Wind Tunnel.
The oil helps researchers &quot;see&quot; the flow patterns when air passes over and around the model. Those patterns are important in determining crucial aircraft characteristics such as lift and drag.
Image Credit: NASA Langley/Preston Martin</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/hwb_oil_visualization_larc_2013.jpg?itok=uqNVNz3e" length="4606498" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/aero/flow_patterns_image.html</guid>
 <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Soyuz Spacecraft Approaches International Space Station</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/soyuz-spacecraft-approaches-international-space-station</link>
 <description>The Soyuz TMA-10M spacecraft approaches the International Space Station, carrying Expedition 37 Soyuz Commander Oleg Kotov, NASA Flight Engineer Michael Hopkins and Russian Flight Engineer Sergey Ryazanskiy. The Soyuz docked to the Poisk Mini-Research Module 2 (MRM2) of the space station at 10:45 p.m. EDT on Sept. 25, 2013.
Image Credit: NASA</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/iss037e002640.jpg?itok=0WPTxI1H" length="554943" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/soyuz-spacecraft-approaches-international-space-station</guid>
 <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>New Expedition 37 Crew Launches to Space Station</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/expedition-37-soyuz-launch</link>
 <description>The Soyuz TMA-10M rocket launches from the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan on Sept. 25 at 4:58 p.m. EDT (2:58 a.m. Kazakh time Sept. 26) carrying Expedition 37 Soyuz Commander Oleg Kotov, NASA Flight Engineer Michael Hopkins and Russian Flight Engineer Sergey Ryazanskiy to the International Space Station.
Image Credit: NASA/Carla Cioffi</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/9940375573_b2f378733c_o.jpg?itok=lfMCnXb_" length="1992596" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/expedition-37-soyuz-launch</guid>
 <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>New Station Crew Ready for Launch</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/new-station-crew-ready-for-launch</link>
 <description>Expedition 37 NASA Flight Engineer Michael Hopkins, far left, Soyuz Commander Oleg Kotov and Russian Flight Engineer Sergey Ryazanskiy, far right, share a laugh at a press conference held at the Cosmonaut Hotel, on Tuesday, Sept. 24, 2013, in Baikonur, Kazakhstan. Launch of the Soyuz rocket is scheduled for Sept. 26 and will send Hopkings, Kotov, Ryazanski on a five and a half-month mission aboard the International Space Station. 
Image Credit: NASA/Carla Cioffi</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/9921443996_40de2d094a_k.jpg?itok=eeRzsN6x" length="1378460" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/new-station-crew-ready-for-launch</guid>
 <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Two Generations of Windblown Sediments on Mars</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/two-generations-of-windblown-sediments-on-mars</link>
 <description>This colorful scene is situated in the Noctis Labyrinthus region of Mars, perched high on the Tharsis rise in the upper reaches of the Valles Marineris canyon system.
Targeting the bright rimmed bedrock knobs, the image also captures the interaction of two distinct types of windblown sediments. Surrounding the bedrock knobs is a network of pale reddish ridges with a complex interlinked morphology. These pale ridges resemble the simpler “transverse aeolian ridges” (called TARs) that are common in the equatorial regions of Mars.
The TARs are still poorly understood, and are variously ascribed to dunes produced by reversing winds, coarse grained ripples, or indurated dust deposits. HiRISE observations of TARs have so far shown that these bedforms are stable over time, suggesting either that they form slowly over much longer time scales than the duration of MRO&#039;s mission, or that they formed in the past during periods of very different atmospheric conditions than the present.
Dark sand dunes comprise the second type of windblown sediment visible in this image. The dark sand dune seen just below the center of the cutout displays features that are common to active sand dunes observed by HiRISE elsewhere on Mars, including sets of small ripples crisscrossing the top of the dune. In many cases, it is the motion of these smaller ripples that drives the advance of Martian sand dunes. The dark dunes are made up of grains composed of iron-rich minerals derived from volcanic rocks on Mars, unlike the pale quartz-rich dunes typical of Earth.
This image clearly shows the dark sand situated on top of the pale TAR network, indicating that the sand dunes are younger than the TARs. Moreover, the fresh appearance of the sand dunes suggest that they are currently active, and may help shape the unusual TAR morphology by sandblasting the TARs in the present day environment.
The original image was acquired on Aug. 31, 2013, by the HiRISE (High Resolution Imaging Science Experiment) instrument aboard NASA&#039;s Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO). HiRISE is operated by the University of Arizona, Tucson.
&gt; More information and image products
Caption Credit: Paul Geissler
	Image Credit: NASA/JPL/University of Arizona</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/esp_033262_1725.jpg?itok=rtNXO2_G" length="4100107" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/two-generations-of-windblown-sediments-on-mars</guid>
 <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Soyuz Rolls Out to Launch Pad</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/soyuz-rolls-out-to-launch-pad-0</link>
 <description>The Soyuz rocket is rolled out to the launch pad by train on Monday, Sept. 23, 2013, at the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan. Launch of the Soyuz rocket is scheduled for Sept. 26 and will send Expedition 37 Soyuz Commander Oleg Kotov, NASA Flight Engineer Michael Hopkins and Russian Flight Engineer Sergei Ryazansky on a five-and-a-half month mission aboard the International Space Station.
Image Credit: NASA/Carla Cioffi</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/9894368115_1271a12361_k.jpg?itok=EyjdSta3" length="1241075" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/soyuz-rolls-out-to-launch-pad-0</guid>
 <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Clues to the Growth of the Colossus in Coma</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/chandra/multimedia/coma-cluster-growth.html</link>
 <description>A team of astronomers has discovered enormous arms of hot gas in the Coma cluster of galaxies by using NASA’s Chandra X-ray Observatory and ESA’s XMM-Newton. These features, which span at least half a million light years, provide insight into how the Coma cluster has grown through mergers of smaller groups and clusters of galaxies to become one of the largest structures in the universe held together by gravity.
A new composite image, with Chandra data in pink and optical data from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey appearing in white and blue, features these spectacular arms. In this image, the Chandra data have been processed so extra detail can be seen.
The X-ray emission is from multimillion-degree gas and the optical data shows galaxies in the Coma Cluster, which contain only about one-sixth the mass in hot gas. Only the brightest X-ray emission is shown here, to emphasize the arms, but the hot gas is present over the entire field of view.
Researchers think that these arms were most likely formed when smaller galaxy clusters had their gas stripped away by the head wind created by the motion of the cluster through the hot gas, in much the same way that the headwind created by a roller coaster blows the hats off riders.
Coma is an unusual galaxy cluster because it contains not one, but two giant elliptical galaxies near its center. These two giant elliptical galaxies are probably the vestiges from each of the two largest clusters that merged with Coma in the past. The researchers also uncovered other signs of past collisions and mergers in the data.
From their length, and the speed of sound in the hot gas (about four million km/hr), the newly discovered X-ray arms are estimated to be about 300 million years old, and they appear to have a rather smooth shape. This gives researchers some clues about the conditions of the hot gas in Coma. Most theoretical models expect that mergers between clusters like those in Coma will produce strong turbulence, like ocean water that has been churned by many passing ships. Instead, the smooth shape of these lengthy arms points to a rather calm setting for the hot gas in the Coma cluster, even after many mergers.
Large-scale magnetic fields are likely responsible for the small amount of turbulence that is present in Coma. Estimating the amount of turbulence in a galaxy cluster has been a challenging problem for astrophysicists. Researchers have found a range of answers, some of them conflicting, and so observations of other clusters are needed.
Two of the arms appear to be connected to a group of galaxies located about two million light years from the center of Coma. One or both of these arms connects to a larger structure seen in the XMM-Newton data, and spans a distance or at least 1.5 million light years. A very thin tail also appears behind one of the galaxies in Coma. This is probably evidence of gas being stripped from a single galaxy, in addition to the groups or clusters that have merged there. 
These new results on the Coma cluster, which incorporate over six days worth of Chandra observing time, will appear in the September 20, 2013, issue of the journal Science. The first author of the paper is Jeremy Sanders from the Max Planck Institute for Extraterrestrial Physics in Garching, Germany. The co-authors are Andy Fabian from Cambridge University in the UK; Eugene Churazov from the Max Planck Institute for Astrophysics in Garching, Germany; Alexander Schekochihin from University of Oxford in the UK; Aurora Simionescu from Stanford University in Stanford, CA; Stephen Walker from Cambridge University in the UK and Norbert Werner from Stanford University in Stanford, CA.
NASA&#039;s Marshall Space Flight Center in Huntsville, Ala., manages the Chandra Program for NASA&#039;s Science Mission Directorate in Washington. The Smithsonian Astrophysical Observatory controls Chandra&#039;s science and flight operations from Cambridge, Mass.
Credits: X-ray: NASA/CXC/MPE/J. Sanders et al; Optical: SDSS
 
› View large image
	› Chandra on Flickr</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/coma.jpg?itok=05emPj7W" length="1776481" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/chandra/multimedia/coma-cluster-growth.html</guid>
 <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Antares Rocket With Cygnus Spacecraft Launches</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/antares-rocket-with-cygnus-spacecraft-launches</link>
 <description>The Orbital Sciences Corporation Antares rocket, with the Cygnus cargo spacecraft aboard, is seen in this false color infrared image, as it launches from Pad-0A of the Mid-Atlantic Regional Spaceport (MARS), Wednesday, Sept. 18, 2013, NASA Wallops Flight Facility, Virginia. Cygnus is on its way to rendezvous with the space station. The spacecraft will deliver about 1,300 pounds (589 kilograms) of cargo, including food and clothing, to the Expedition 37 crew.
		Image Credit: NASA/Bill Ingalls
		Editor&#039;s Note: This image is a false color infrared image made from a modified digital SLR camera.</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/9806274146_69f66f9528_k.jpg?itok=nfbAuuYb" length="1646899" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/antares-rocket-with-cygnus-spacecraft-launches</guid>
 <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Antares Rocket With Cygnus Spacecraft Launches From Wallops Flight Facility</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/antares-rocket-with-cygnus-spacecraft-launches-from-wallops-flight-facility</link>
 <description>Sept. 18, 2013 -- The Orbital Sciences Corporation Antares rocket, with the Cygnus cargo spacecraft aboard, is seen as it launches from Pad-0A of the Mid-Atlantic Regional Spaceport (MARS), NASA Wallops Flight Facility, Va., at 10:58 a.m. EDT on Wed., Sept. 18, 2013. Cygnus is on its way to rendezvous with the International Space Station. The spacecraft will deliver about 1,300 pounds (589 kilograms) of cargo, including food and clothing, to the Expedition 37 crew.
Image Credit: NASA/Bill Ingalls</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/201309180001hq.jpeg?itok=y8VbP4dD" length="1793852" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/antares-rocket-with-cygnus-spacecraft-launches-from-wallops-flight-facility</guid>
 <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Flag at Half-Staff at Wallops Flight Facility</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/flag-at-half-staff-at-wallops-flight-facility</link>
 <description>A United States flag is flown at half-staff just outside the Mid-Atlantic Regional Spaceport (MARS) Pad-0A with the Orbital Sciences Corporation Antares rocket, Tuesday, Sept. 17, 2013, NASA Wallops Flight Facility, Virginia. President Obama directed Monday that flags be lowered to half-staff to pay tribute to the victims of &quot;the senseless acts of violence&quot; perpetrated at the Washington Navy Yard. NASA&#039;s commercial space partner, Orbital Sciences Corporation, is targeting a Sept. 18 launch of the Cygnus cargo spacecraft, demonstration cargo resupply mission, to the International Space Station.
Image Credit: NASA/Bill Ingalls</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/201309170003hq.jpg?itok=6NKiubS_" length="2546512" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/flag-at-half-staff-at-wallops-flight-facility</guid>
 <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
